Once upon a time in South Central L.A... It ain't no fairy tale.
Boyz n the Hood is a crime, drama film directed by John Singleton.
In the middle of the Los Angeles ghetto, drugs,
robberies and shootings dominate everyday life.
During these times, Furious tries to raise his son Tre to be a decent person.
Tre's friends, on the other hand, have little regard for the law and
drag the entire neighborhood into a street war...
Tré Styles, played by Cuba Gooding Jr..
Furious Styles, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Doughboy, played by Ice Cube.
Ricky Baker, played by Morris Chestnut.
Reva Styles, played by Angela Bassett.
Brandi, played by Nia Long.
Boyz n the Hood is a 1991 American coming-of-age hood crime drama film written
and directed by John Singleton in his feature directorial debut.
It stars Ice Cube (in his film debut), Cuba Gooding Jr., Morris Chestnut (in his film debut), and Laurence Fishburne (credited as
Larry Fishburne), with Nia Long, Tyra Ferrell, Regina King (in her film debut), and Angela Bassett in supporting roles.
Boyz n the Hood follows Tre Styles (Gooding), who is sent to live with his father Furious Styles (Fishburne) in South Central Los
Angeles, where he reunites with his childhood friends while surrounded by the neighborhood's booming gang culture.
The film's title is a reference to the 1987 Eazy-E rap
song of the same name, written by Ice Cube.
Singleton initially developed the film as a requirement for his application to film school
in 1986 and sold the script to Columbia Pictures upon graduation in 1990.
During writing, he drew inspiration from his own life and from the lives
of people he knew and insisted he direct the project.
Principal photography began in September 1990 and was filmed
on location from October to November 1990.
The film features breakout roles for Ice Cube, Gooding Jr., Chestnut, and Long.
Boyz n the Hood was screened in the Un Certain Regard
section at the 1991 Cannes Film Festival.
It premiered in Los Angeles on July 2, 1991, and was
theatrically released in the United States ten days later.
The film became a critical and commercial success, grossing $57.5 million in North America and earning
nominations for Best Director and Best Original Screenplay at the 64th Academy Awards.
Singleton became the youngest person and the first African
American to be nominated for Best Director.
In 2002, the United States Library of Congress deemed it "culturally, historically, or
aesthetically significant" and selected it for preservation in the National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of street gang, gangster, rapper, ghetto, street war.
The tone is emotional and intense.